Gangster. Media darling. Model citizen.
Edwin Boyd: Citizen Gangster is a crime, drama,
history film directed by Nathan Morlando.
Based on a real WWII vet and family man turned bank robber.
Disillusioned by his post war circumstances, Eddie Boyd is torn between the need to provide for
his young family and an unfulfilled dream to head to Hollywood to become a star.
He discovers a way to do both, robbing banks Hollywood style, but his
dream leads him down a path of danger and tragedy.
Eddie Boyd, played by Scott Speedman.
Doreen Boyd, played by Kelly Reilly.
Lenny Jackson, played by Kevin Durand.
Val Kozak, played by Joseph Cross.
Willie 'The Clown' Jackson, played by Brendan Fletcher.
Mary Mitchell, played by Charlotte Sullivan.
Citizen Gangster is a 2011 Canadian biographical drama film
directed and written by Nathan Morlando.
Scott Speedman stars as Canadian gangster and
alleged murderer Edwin Alonzo Boyd.
The film originally premiered at the 2011 Toronto International Film Festival under the
title Edwin Boyd, but was retitled Citizen Gangster in general release.
The film explores themes of police brutality, toronto,
canada, bus driver, prison escape, true crime.
The tone is dark and emotional.